DATA VARIABLES 

* long = longitude 
* lat = latitude 

Time
* year 
* time_period = (Hist, LT, NT) 
—> Hist = (1980 - 2018) historic or observed 
—> LT = (2060 - 2099) Long term 
—> NT = (2021 - 2059) Near-term

*(winter: December–February; spring: March–May; summer: June–August; fall: September–November)*

Prediction Categories: 
* rcp = projected greenhouse gas concentrations in the future (higher = more greenhouse gas aka CO2)
—> historic = not predicted cause its in the past 
—> 4.5 = mid range/normal CO2 emissions 
—> 8.5 = high range of CO2
* scenario = model + rcp pairing. The model is used to simulate a response to global climate change by the increase of CO2 emissions (it’s just categorical)

Vegetation: 
* treecanopy = % of tree canopy coverage in the area
* ann_herb = % of annual herbaceous coverage
* bare = % of bare ground
* herb = % coverage of herbaceous plants 
* litter = % coverage of plant litter aka dead plant material
* shrub = % coverage of shrubs 

* dry_soil_days_summer_whole = dry soil days in entire soil profile during the summer 
* evap_summer = centimeters of evaporation in summer from soil, litter, canopy, surface water, and snowpack
* extreme_short_term_dry_stress_summer_whole = extreme short term dry stress for the whole soil profile in the summer. max temp in C of 10 hottest days where soil is “semi-dry” 
* frost days winter = count of frost days in winter
* non_dry_swa_summer_whole = mean non-dry soil water availability during the summer

Climate:
* ppt_winter = precipitation in winter (cm)
* ppt_summer = precipitation in summer (cm)
* ppt_annual = precipitation in the year (cm)
* t_winter = avg temp in winter
* t_summer = avg temp in summer 
* t_annual = avg temp in the year
* tmax_summer = max temp in summer 
* tmin_winter = min temp in winter
* vwc_winter_whole = median volumetric water in whole soup profile during the winter (m3/m^3)
* vwc_spring_whole = median volumetric water in whole soup profile during the spring (m3/m^3)
* vwc_summer_whole = median volumetric water in whole soup profile during the summer (m3/m^3)
* vwc_fall_whole = median volumetric water in whole soup profile during the fall (m3/m^3)